For nearly a century, the enduring symbol of the University of Maryland has been a
humble diamond-backed terrapin, Testudo.
Testudo first took form as a 300-pound bronze sculpture, a gift from the Class of 1933,
first unveiled outside of Ritchie Coliseum.
The sculpture immediately became an iconic part of campus life, and the tradition of
rubbing Testudo's nose for good luck was born.
Testudo might have been too popular.
The original sculpture was captured 12 times.
The terp nappings launched police investigations as far away as Reno, Nevada.
Hoping to keep Testudo at home, the University placed the sculpture on a pedestal and weighed
it down with 700 pounds of cement.
The original statue now sits proudly outside of McKelden Library.
In 1965, the Student Government Association introduced Testudo II, and this turtle could
really get around.
The 15-foot-long mobile version appeared on national television that year, just before
a home football game against rival Penn State.
Over the years, Testudo has taken many forms, sticking a neck out for us all.
Our fearless mascot has shown us how to lead with patience and wisdom and resilience.
No matter how the University evolves and grows over the next century, one thing is certain.
Testudo will be there to help us guide the way, fearlessly forward.